https://birdwatchireland.ie/about-us/governance/privacy-statement/

Hit enter to search or ESC to close
COVID-19 Emergency Fundraising AppealIreland's birds have helped us . . .
please, return the favour
Donate now
Irish Garden Bird SurveyHelp us by counting your garden birds this winter
Find out more
Welcome to BirdWatch IrelandProtecting birds and biodiversity
Shop
BirdWatch Ireland is committed to protect the rights and privacy of individuals in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Data Protection Act 2018.
Privacy Policy
BirdWatch Ireland is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the BirdWatch Ireland Web site and governs data collection and usage. By using the BirdWatch Ireland website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.
Collection of your Personal Information
BirdWatch Ireland collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. BirdWatch Ireland also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.
There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by BirdWatch Ireland. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by BirdWatch Ireland for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the BirdWatch Ireland Web site.
Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through BirdWatch Ireland public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: BirdWatch Ireland does not read any of your private online communications.
BirdWatch Ireland encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from BirdWatch Ireland so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. BirdWatch Ireland is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the BirdWatch Ireland and BirdWatch Ireland family of Web sites.
Use of your Personal Information
BirdWatch Ireland collects and uses your personal information to operate the BirdWatch Ireland Web site and deliver the services you have requested. BirdWatch Ireland also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from BirdWatch Ireland and its affiliates. BirdWatch Ireland may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.
BirdWatch Ireland does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. BirdWatch Ireland may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, BirdWatch Ireland may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to BirdWatch Ireland, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.
BirdWatch Ireland does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.
BirdWatch Ireland keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within BirdWatch Ireland, in order to determine what BirdWatch Ireland services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within BirdWatch Ireland to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.
BirdWatch Ireland Web sites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on BirdWatch Ireland or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of BirdWatch Ireland; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of BirdWatch Ireland, or the public.
Use of Cookies
The BirdWatch Ireland Web site use “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.
One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize BirdWatch Ireland pages, or register with BirdWatch Ireland site or services, a cookie helps BirdWatch Ireland to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same BirdWatch Ireland Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the BirdWatch Ireland features that you customized.
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the BirdWatch Ireland services or Web sites you visit.
Security of your Personal Information
BirdWatch Ireland secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. BirdWatch Ireland secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.
Changes to this Statement
BirdWatch Ireland will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. BirdWatch Ireland encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how BirdWatch Ireland is protecting your information.
Contact Information
BirdWatch Ireland welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that BirdWatch Ireland has not adhered to this Statement, please contact BirdWatch Ireland at info@birdwatchireland.ie. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
Access Requests
Please see below, sample wording for letter to access data held under the General Data Protection Regulaton (GDPR) and the Data Protection Act 2018.
When requesting information, it is important to give any details that will help the person to identify you and find your data – For example any previous address or your date of birth; and be clear about which details you are looking for if you only want certain information. This will help BirdWatch Ireland to respond more quickly.
There is no charge to provide a copy of the information. However, if any further copies are requested by the data subject, or if the request is manifestly unfounded or excessive, we reserve the right to charge a reasonable fee based on the administration costs.
To:
CEO,
BirdWatch Ireland,
Unit 20, Block D,
Bullford Business Campus,
Kilcoole,
Co. Wicklow
Dear Sirs.
I wish to make an access request under Article 15 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) for a copy of any information you keep about me, on computer or in manual form in relation to…
[Insert relevant information to assist BirdWatch Ireland to identify you and find your data]
Yours faithfully,
[Name]
[Address]
© 2020 BirdWatch Ireland.
What to do if you find a baby bird or injured bird?
